Data Privacy Information
========================

Name and address of the data controller
---------------------------------------

As the data controller for data processing, we:

Bigpoint GmbH

Sachsenstraße 20

20097 Hamburg

Germany

Email: [info@bigpoint.net](mailto:info@bigpoint.net) (no support)

implement all the technical and organisational measures to ensure the protection of your data.

Name and address of the data protection officer
-----------------------------------------------

Data protection agency

Maximilian Hartung

Frauentorstraße 9

86152 Augsburg

Germany

Tel.: +49 821 90786458

privacy@bigpoint.net

### General

This Data Privacy Information informs you of which personal data is collected by Bigpoint in the context of our websites, our apps and the games and other services provided by us (jointly referred to as the “Online Offer”). It also explains how such data is processed and used. The protection of your personal information is important to us.

Your data is protected against unauthorised access and loss through the use of various electronic, technical, physical, administrative and contractual measures. Bigpoint has taken the necessary technical and organisational precautions to ensure that the regulations for data privacy are respected both internally and by external service providers.

This Data Privacy Information contains transparent and clear information to ensure that visitors to our site and customers are well informed regarding the collection, processing and use of their personal data.

What is personal data?
----------------------

Personal data is any information relating to an identified or identifiable natural person (e.g. name, address, telephone number, date of birth or email address).

Protection of vital interests

Art. 6, para 1 , lit. d GDPR serves as the legal basis should the vital interests of the data subject or another natural person require the processing of personal data.

What data do we collect?
------------------------

**Usage data that is automatically collected**

Usage data is automatically collected when you use our websites, forums and games; the information in these log files is automatically transmitted by your device.

The following data is collected when you visit a website:

* IP address of the computer from which the website was accessed
* Date, time, duration and frequency of use
* Name of the websites used
* Volume of data transferred
* Operating system and browser name and version
* URL from which you were directed to our site (origin URL)
* Access status (request successful, file not found, etc.)

The following data is collected when you open an app:

* IP address of the device from which the app was accessed
* Date, time, duration and frequency of use
* Device type, screen resolution, screen size and pixel density
* Store ID
* Volume of data transferred
* Operating system and app name and version
* Access status (request successful, file not found, etc.)

**Contact requests**

You can send us a message using the contact form on our website, by email or via the support requests for our games. The name, postal address, email address, user ID, IP address (if using the contact form), date and time and the content of the message will be processed if such data is included in your message.

**Game forums**

We provide forums for our games on which players can exchange ideas, find help with the games and ask questions. The following data is processed when you use a forum: the username, email address, password, date of registration, possibly a profile picture and the content of the forum posts.

**Newsletters**

We send newsletters to inform you about our games and game innovations. We process the email address, user ID and information regarding when and from which IP address the newsletter was opened from players who have consented to receive them.

**Use of our game offers**

When you use our games, the login data (username, user ID, password), game progress, game statistics and game usage, communication data (for in-game messages or use of the chat function) and, if paid services are used in the game or paid items are purchased, payment data (credit card information, bank details, PayPal data, etc.) are processed in addition to the usage data that is automatically collected (see above),

If you have been a user of our games for a long time, please note that we also use data from our predecessor company, Bigpoint S.à.r.l. & Co, SCS, 10A rue Henri M. Schnadt, L-2530 Luxembourg. This is the inventory data we require to enable us to continue providing our games to you without interruption (this applies in particular to game progress, game scores and information about the purchase and billing of services).
-------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------

For what purpose do we use your data and what is the legal basis for such use?
------------------------------------------------------------------------------

**Automatically collected usage data**

We collect usage data to ensure the functionality of our websites, forums and games.

Should any suspicion arise of a breach of the terms of use, we store the IP address and relevant Internet information to trace and clarify any misuse of player accounts.

The legal basis for this data processing is a balancing of interests in accordance with Art. 6, para 1, lit. f GDPR. We have a legitimate interest with respect to the secure provision of our websites, forums and games and in the economic analysis and operation of this service.

**Contact requests**

Personal data is processed to enable us to respond to your request.

The legal basis for this data processing is a legitimate interest in accordance with Art. 6, para 1, lit. f GDPR. We have a legitimate interest in responding to your request and in fulfilling your legitimate interest in receiving a response to your request.

**Game forums**

The data in the gaming forums is processed to make the forums available to you and to identify the users of the forum.

The legal basis for processing forum registration data is the performance of the contract in accordance with Art. 6, para 1, lit. b GDPR. The legal basis for processing and storing forum posts is a legitimate interest in accordance with Art. 6, para 1, lit. f GDPR. We have a legitimate interest in retaining the information collected in the forums for the users of our games.

**Newsletters**

We send newsletters to inform you about our games. The data collected in addition to the email address is processed to analyse the sending of newsletters.

The legal basis for sending the newsletter is your consent in accordance with Art. 6, para 1, lit. a GDPR. The legal basis for further processing is our legitimate interest in providing the optimal information about our games (Art. 6, para 1, lit. f GDPR). Should you unsubscribe from the newsletter, we will save this to ensure you do not receive it in future. The legal basis for this is our legitimate interest in ensuring that the processing complies with data protection regulations in accordance with Art. 6, para 1, lit. f GDPR.

**Use of our game offers**

When you use our games, we process data to ensure the functionality of the games, to manage game scores, correct any errors or malfunctions, prevent fraud and abuse and to improve the gaming experience. We also use the data to assert legal claims and to defend ourselves in legal disputes as well as for self-promotion and third-party advertising. In the event of late payments, we reserve the right to authorise a debt collection agency to enforce our claims.

The legal basis for the processing of data to use our games and to assert claims is the performance of the contract in accordance with Art. 6, para 1, lit. b GDPR. The legal basis for data we process to improve our games or to prevent fraud is our legitimate interest in improving our games (Art. 6, para 1, lit. f GDPR). The legal basis for self-promotion and third-party advertising is your consent in accordance with Art. 6, para 1, lit. a GDPR or, to the extent permitted by law, our legitimate interest in providing information about our games (Art. 6, para 1, lit. f GDPR).

**Protection of vital interests**

Art. 6, para 1, lit. d GDPR serves as the legal basis should the vital interests of the data subject or another natural person require the processing of personal data.

**Prevention of criminal activity**

Data processing is carried out to prevent, investigate and report criminal offences, e.g. fraud, credit card misuse, or identity fraud on the legal basis of our legitimate interest in the secure provision of our games (Art. 6, para 1, lit. f GDPR).

**Fulfilment of our legal obligations**

In cases where we are under a legal obligation to disclose data, e.g. to law enforcement authorities, or where we have to fulfil statutory retention periods, data processing is carried out on the legal basis of Art. 6, para 1, lit. c GDPR.
-----------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------

Cookies
-------

We and our partners use cookies and similar technologies that fulfil the same functions as cookies (“Cookies”) in our Online Offer, among others to improve our Online Offer, to improve the user experience and to carry out personalised online advertising. Cookies are small text files that contain data from websites visited, e.g. the language settings on a website or the login status. Cookies are stored on your device by the browser you are using for their respective lifetime. Some Cookies are automatically deleted after the browser session has ended (“session” Cookies), while others are stored for a specified time or permanently in the user's browser and delete themselves automatically after the specified time has elapsed (“temporary” or “permanent” Cookies).

We may sometimes request your consent for the use of Cookies by us and our partners to save and retrieve information on your device. If you provide your consent, we will process your data on the legal basis of the declared consent. In certain cases, the data processed using Cookies is processed based on our legitimate interests or those of our partners, or if the use of Cookies is essential to fulfil our contractual obligations to you (e.g. the secure operation of our Online Offer).

You can revoke your consent to the use of Cookies at any time with effect for the future. To do this, simply change your selection in our cookie manager, which you can access via the "Cookie Settings" of our Online Offer.

You can also disable the storage of Cookies in your browser settings and delete the Cookies saved in your browser at any time. However, please note that our Online Offer may not function, or only to a limited extent, without the use of Cookies.

In addition, please note that objections to the use of Cookies are sometimes implemented through opt-out Cookies. Should you delete all the Cookies, any objections may therefore no longer be taken into account and must be obtained from you again.

Data transfer and service providers
-----------------------------------

We will treat your data as strictly confidential and will not disclose it to third parties without your consent or unless we are legally permitted to do so. We may, in individual cases, be legally obliged to disclose your information, for example to investigating authorities, whereby disclosure will only take place to the extent required by law. We use the companies affiliated with the Bigpoint Group and/or third parties to provide services on our behalf. This is mainly for payment transactions by external service providers (PayPal, Global Collect, etc.) and, in the event of default, by a debt collection company.

We store your personal data in cloud systems to ensure the secure and efficient management of the data. We use the Alicloud cloud service operated by Alibaba Cloud. The servers on which your data is stored are located within the European Union, which ensures that your data is subject to the strict requirements of the GDPR and processed within the EU. The data collected from users of our game servers in North America is stored on a server in the United States of America.

Moreover, we provide your data to affiliated companies of the Bigpoint Group for marketing purposes and to further develop and improve our games. These affiliated companies of the Bigpoint Group and external companies are under an obligation to handle your data confidentially and securely and may only use your data insofar as it is required for completing the task they have been assigned. Service providers are generally involved as processors who are only authorised to process the personal data of users of this Online Offer in accordance with our explicit instructions.

Period of storage/retention periods
-----------------------------------

We store your data for as long as this is necessary for the provision of our Online Offer and the associated services, or if we have a legitimate interest in the further retention of such. In all other cases, we will delete your personal information except for data we may be required to retain in accordance with the contractual or statutory requirements (e.g. tax or commercial purposes, invoices, etc.). Contractual retention periods may also arise from contracts with third parties (e.g. owners of copyrights and ancillary copyrights). We will block any data that is subject to a retention period until the expiry of the relevant period.

We generally store IP addresses and relevant Internet information for a period of up to six months. Should the stability and operational reliability of our system be compromised, or should a suspicion arise, for example, of a breach of the games rules through the use of bots, we will store the respective log files for as long as necessary to ensure the security of the system or to clarify any suspected fraud.

Game information and partner offers
-----------------------------------

When you check the box next to “Game information and partner offers”, you are granting us your express consent to receive this information. Your consent will be recorded and saved and may be revoked at any time by using our contact form ([www.bigpoint.net/support/](https://www.bigpoint.net/support/)).

Surveys
-------

We carry out satisfaction surveys to improve our Online Offer. We therefore collect and process your data as stated in the declaration of consent or the surveys. The legal basis for the processing of this data is your consent in accordance with Art. 6, para 1, lit. a GDPR. You can withdraw your consent to the processing of your data at any time, e.g. via our contact form (www.bigpoint.net/support/). We use the services of LimeSurvey GmbH, Papenreye 63, 22453 Hamburg ("LimeSurvey") to conduct the surveys. We have concluded a data processing agreement with LimeSurvey in accordance with Art. 28 GDPR. The data collected from the surveys is stored on LimeSurvey servers at Host Europe GmbH in Germany.

Google Analytics
----------------

This website uses Google Analytics and Google Analytics reports to evaluate demographic characteristics and interests. These services are provided by Google LLC (“Google”). Google Analytics uses “cookies”, which are text files placed on your computer to help the website analyse how users use the site. The information generated by the cookie about your use of the website is normally transmitted to, and stored by, Google on servers in the United States. If, however, you activate the Anonymise IP option on this website, Google will truncate your IP address, so it only locates you within the member states of the European Union or other contracting states of the European Economic Area. Only in rare cases will the full IP address be transmitted to a Google server in the USA and truncated there. Google will use this information to evaluate your use of the website, to compile reports on website activity for website operators and to provide other services relating to website activity and Internet usage. The operator of this website will use information gathered via interest-related advertising and third-party visitor data (e.g. age, gender and interests) for the purpose of evaluation to find out more about the users of this website. No data that can be attributed to a specific person will be used here; this is for the exclusive purpose of a statistical evaluation of anonymous data sets. Google will not associate your IP address as transmitted by Google Analytics with any other data held by Google. You may refuse the use of cookies by selecting the appropriate settings in our cookie manager or your browser software; please note however that, if you do this, you may not be able to use the full functionality of this website. Furthermore, you can prohibit Google from collecting and analysing the data generated by the cookie about your use of the website (including your IP address) by downloading and installing the browser plugin available here [http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout](http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=de). Should you wish to adjust or prevent the analysis of your demographic or interest-based information, you can disable Google Analytics display ads and adjust the ads in the Google Display Network: [https://www.google.com/settings/ads](https://www.google.com/settings/ads?hl=de).

If you access this website via a mobile device (smartphone, tablet, etc.) you may object to the use of your data by Google by clicking a separate link in the dialog box displayed.

Social media plugins
--------------------

Facebook

Various Facebook links are embedded on our website; this web presence is operated exclusively by Facebook Inc., 1601 S California Ave, Palo Alto, CA 94304, USA (Facebook).

In the context of our web presence, these links are identified by the Facebook logo or by the phrase ‘Like’ (no Facebook plugins are used).

If a user clicks one of these links, the Facebook plugins will be activated and will establish a direct connection via the user’s browser to a Facebook server.

If the user clicks (follows) one of the links while visiting our website and is logged into their personal Facebook account, Facebook will be notified that the user has visited our website. Facebook may link your visit to the website to your account.

This information will be transmitted to Facebook and stored there. To prevent this, the user must log out of their Facebook account before clicking the link. The functions embedded in the links by Facebook, in particular the transfer of data and user information, are not activated when you visit our website, but only when you click the corresponding links.

The purpose and scope of data collection via Facebook, the processing and use of such data at Facebook, your respective rights and personal setting options to protect your privacy are available in the Facebook privacy settings section (http://de-de.facebook.com/privacy/explanation.php).

Please contact us if you have further questions regarding the collection, processing or use of your personal data and regarding the disclosure, correction, blocking or deleting of data in this respect.

Facebook Connect

We're offering you the opportunity to register for our services through Facebook Connect. To do this, you will be redirected to Facebook where you can log in with your Facebook user data. Your Facebook account will then be linked to our services. Depending on your Facebook settings, linking your account will allow the following data to be transmitted to us and/or retrieved by us: name, date of birth and email address.

We will use this information exclusively for the purposes of identification and contract processing. For more information on Facebook Connect and the privacy settings, please refer to the Data Privacy Policy and Terms of Use of Facebook Inc.

Mobile apps
-----------

Our apps are provided through various app and software platforms, including the Apple App Store, the Google Play Store and social networks like Facebook. If you access, register with or use the platform or social network, personal data may be collected and used by the respective platform or social network over which we basically have no influence. You can find all the relevant information in the data protection guidelines or provisions of the respective platform or social network.

IT security
-----------

With the help of an IT security provider, we use Cookies to collect and process specific data anonymously about the features of the terminal device used by the user (“device-specific data”), raw data from the TCP/IP connection and data on the use of our website to prevent the misuse of our services.

Initially, the IP address is also collected and processed but encrypted within a few seconds. The information is stored with the IT security provider in a database for the prevention of fraud.

If you conclude a contract on our website that involves a fee, or if the conclusion of a contract that involves a fee is approaching (e.g. at the beginning of the checkout process), we can access a risk evaluation regarding the terminal device you are using from the IT security provider's database which has been stored there.

The risk evaluation is used, not exclusively, as a basis for deciding whether a contract for pecuniary interest can be concluded.

Should we detect that a user is abusing, or has attempted to abuse, our services, we shall also transmit the data collected to the IT security provider.

Right of revocation, deletion of data
-------------------------------------

If you have given consent to process personal data, you can withdraw this consent at any time.

Bigpoint deletes your personal data insofar as it is no longer required or if you have requested the deletion of such data. Please note that data cannot be deleted if legal or other requirements to retain the data exist, or if we require the data to bill our services.

Information on data protection, right to information and the correction, deletion and blocking of data
------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------

Should you have any general questions regarding this Data Privacy Information and data protection, or if you would like to query, correct, block or delete your personal data in accordance with the legal stipulations, please contact us via email or post, stating your user ID, username, email address and, if applicable, your game. You can contact us or the data protection officer directly via the contact details at the top of this Data Privacy Information.

Right of appeal to the regulatory body
--------------------------------------

You have the right to file a complaint with a data protection authority. You can contact the competent data protection authority for your respective place of residence or region, or the authority which is responsible for us, which is: the Hamburg Commission for Data Protection and Freedom of Information, Klosterwall 6 (Block C), 20095 Hamburg, Tel.: 040 / 428 54 – 4040, Fax: 040 / 428 54 – 4000, email: [mailbox@datenschutz.hamburg.de](mailto:mailbox@datenschutz.hamburg.de)

Security provisions
-------------------

All the employees in our company receive regular training in data protection and are committed to data protection. Our computer centre and our in-house EDP department continuously adapt the technical security precautions to the current security conditions and requirements. Both are subject to constant monitoring by our internal procedures and the data protection officer. Nevertheless, Internet technologies may have security loopholes that cannot guarantee 100% full protection, and users can therefore submit data to us via other methods, e.g. fax.

Changes and updates to the Data Privacy Information
---------------------------------------------------

We would ask you to keep regularly informed regarding the content of this Data Privacy Information. We will amend this Data Privacy Information if any changes to the data processing carried out by us make this necessary. We will notify you when such changes require your cooperation (e.g. consent) or other individual notification.

If we provide addresses and contact information of companies and organisations in this Data Privacy Information, please note that the addresses may change over time, so please check the information before contacting us.

Version date: 30/09/2024
